<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Messages</title>
    <link>https://tjfinney-messages.netlify.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Messages</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://tjfinney-messages.netlify.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sign of Jonah</title>
      <link>https://tjfinney-messages.netlify.com/posts/2019-04-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tjfinney-messages.netlify.com/posts/2019-04-20/</guid>
      <description>Thank you all for being here. Today I&amp;rsquo;d like to talk about the Easter holidays. I&amp;rsquo;m not going to talk about these Easter holidays but about the original Easter holy days, three days that changed everything.
Give us a sign In chapter twelve of Matthew&amp;rsquo;s Gospel we find Jesus in a dispute with the religious authorities. Here&amp;rsquo;s how it happened:
 Then a demon-possessed man who was blind and mute was brought to Jesus, and He healed him, so that the mute man spoke and saw.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cups of wine</title>
      <link>https://tjfinney-messages.netlify.com/posts/2019-03-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tjfinney-messages.netlify.com/posts/2019-03-30/</guid>
      <description>What Christians now call communion or the Last Supper began as a Passover Meal that Jesus shared with his disciples the night before he was crucified. Jesus told his disciples to remember him whenever they had that meal. At a previous service we looked at certain aspects of the bread. Tonight we will look at certain aspects of the wine.
The Passover meal has four cups of wine but we will only have two cups tonight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poor man&#39;s bread</title>
      <link>https://tjfinney-messages.netlify.com/posts/2019-02-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tjfinney-messages.netlify.com/posts/2019-02-23/</guid>
      <description>Bread and wine What Christians call communion or the Lord&amp;rsquo;s supper started off as a Passover meal that Jesus ate with his disciples on the night before he went to the cross.
During communion we eat something like bread and drink something like wine. Communion is a symbolic meal, and tonight we will look at the symbolism of the bread. Next month I hope to look at the symbolism of the wine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beautiful feet</title>
      <link>https://tjfinney-messages.netlify.com/posts/2019-02-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tjfinney-messages.netlify.com/posts/2019-02-09/</guid>
      <description>Tonight we will look at something from Luke&amp;rsquo;s Gospel, which tells us about what happened once when Jesus was invited to a meal. Here is how it starts:
 One of the Pharisees invited him to a meal. When he arrived at the Pharisee&amp;rsquo;s house and took his place at table, a woman came in, who had a bad name in the town. She had heard he was dining with the Pharisee and had brought with her an alabaster jar of ointment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The evil eye</title>
      <link>https://tjfinney-messages.netlify.com/posts/2018-12-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tjfinney-messages.netlify.com/posts/2018-12-29/</guid>
      <description>The ten commandments Our church has been going through the ten commandments and now we have reached the last one. God gave these commandments to the Israelites after he set them free. The commandments tell us how to honour God and respect each other. A country that obeys these commands will be set free, but any nation that ignores them is in danger of reverting to slavery.
The children of Israel had just been set free from Egypt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This little light</title>
      <link>https://tjfinney-messages.netlify.com/posts/2018-10-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tjfinney-messages.netlify.com/posts/2018-10-13/</guid>
      <description>Telling God&amp;rsquo;s story Christians are meant to be evangelists. That means we are meant to tell people the good news. The word evangelist comes from the Greek ευαγγελιον, which means good news. The word gospel also means good news but has German ancestry (as do a lot of English words).1
If you are like me then you have trouble being an evangelist. I find evangelism hard, like going to the dentist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gentleness</title>
      <link>https://tjfinney-messages.netlify.com/posts/2018-08-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tjfinney-messages.netlify.com/posts/2018-08-04/</guid>
      <description>Introduction We have been hearing about a well known part of Paul&amp;rsquo;s Letter to the Galatians, where he says:
 But the fruit of the Spirit is love, joy, peace, patience, kindness, goodness, faithfulness, gentleness, self-control; against such things there is no law.
 Gal 5.22-23
The Galatians were Celts, the same people whose descendants still live in Scotland, Ireland, and Wales. What were they doing all the way over in Asia Minor?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1 Peter 1.1</title>
      <link>https://tjfinney-messages.netlify.com/posts/2018-06-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tjfinney-messages.netlify.com/posts/2018-06-09/</guid>
      <description>A general letter The First Letter of Peter is one of the seven General Letters in the New Testament: James; First and Second Peter; First, Second, and Third John; and Jude. These letters are called &amp;ldquo;General&amp;rdquo; because they are addressed to general groups of people instead of particular ones. Here&amp;rsquo;s an example of a general letter:
&amp;ldquo;To Everyone living in Australia, treat foreigners as well as you treat your own people and love them as much as you love yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Astonished</title>
      <link>https://tjfinney-messages.netlify.com/posts/2018-04-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tjfinney-messages.netlify.com/posts/2018-04-07/</guid>
      <description>Introduction We have been looking at what the Four Gospels say about what happened on Easter Sunday, and this week we are looking at Mark&amp;rsquo;s account.
Mark&amp;rsquo;s Gospel appears to be an eye witness account of Jesus from the time he chose his first followers to when they ran away.
Eusebius, who wrote a history of the church around 300 AD, tells us what someone named Papias wrote about Mark.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One thing worth pursuing</title>
      <link>https://tjfinney-messages.netlify.com/posts/2018-01-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tjfinney-messages.netlify.com/posts/2018-01-27/</guid>
      <description>A letter from prison We&amp;rsquo;ve been going through Paul&amp;rsquo;s Letter to the Philippians and today we are up to chapter three. Paul wrote this letter from prison, and he seems to have doubts about getting out alive: To me life means Christ and death means gain Phil 1.21.
Some think he was in prison in Rome, others in Ephesus, and others in Caesarea. I think the Letter fits well with his imprisonment in Caesarea after being arrested in the temple at Jerusalem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XXIII</title>
      <link>https://tjfinney-messages.netlify.com/posts/2017-11-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tjfinney-messages.netlify.com/posts/2017-11-12/</guid>
      <description>A favourite The Psalms are one of the best-loved parts of the Bible, and one of the best-loved Psalms is Psalm 23 (XXIII in Roman numerals). &amp;ldquo;Psalm&amp;rdquo; means &amp;ldquo;song&amp;rdquo;, so what better way to introduce it than to sing it?
The Lord’s my Shepherd, I’ll not want. He makes me down to lie In pastures green; He leadeth me The quiet waters by. My soul He doth restore again; And me to walk doth make Within the paths of righteousness, Even for His own Name’s sake.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First words</title>
      <link>https://tjfinney-messages.netlify.com/posts/2016-08-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tjfinney-messages.netlify.com/posts/2016-08-10/</guid>
      <description>Four Gospels The Four Gospels are four versions of the Good News concerning Jesus Christ. In them the first generation of Christians tell us what they witnessed when Jesus came to town.
We have been handed four Gospels, those according to Matthew, Mark, Luke, and John. These are the written accounts of the Good News concerning Jesus Christ handed down to us by the first generation of Christians. They are from the time of the apostles, and can be linked with four early Christian leaders (or the missions they headed): James the Just, first bishop of Jerusalem; Peter, taking the Gospel to Jews beyond the Holy Land; Paul, apostle to the Gentiles (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Galatians</title>
      <link>https://tjfinney-messages.netlify.com/posts/2015-12-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tjfinney-messages.netlify.com/posts/2015-12-01/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;You stupid Galatians! Who put the evil eye on you?&amp;rdquo; That&amp;rsquo;s what Paul says in his letter to the Galatians. Wikipedia says &amp;ldquo;The Galatians were a Celtic people that dwelt mainly in the north central regions of Asia Minor or Anatolia, in what was known as Galatia, in today&amp;rsquo;s Turkey.&amp;rdquo;1 Back then people who spoke Celtic languages could be found all the way from Scotland in the West to the Roman province of Galatia in the East.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genuine love</title>
      <link>https://tjfinney-messages.netlify.com/posts/2015-04-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tjfinney-messages.netlify.com/posts/2015-04-11/</guid>
      <description>No one is right  The greatest proof that the Bible is inspired is that it has withstood so much bad preaching! &amp;ndash; A. T. Robertson
 No one is right, no one. All have gone wrong. Jews and non-Jews alike have a problem &amp;ndash; they do not measure up to their own standards, let alone God&amp;rsquo;s. What can we do about this? Make a big sacrifice? No, it&amp;rsquo;s not enough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jesus Christ&#39;s Mission</title>
      <link>https://tjfinney-messages.netlify.com/posts/2013-06-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tjfinney-messages.netlify.com/posts/2013-06-15/</guid>
      <description>Jesus announces his mission The Gospel of Luke tells us that Jesus&amp;rsquo;s public work began after his baptism by John the Baptist in the Jordan River. People thought that John the Baptist might be the Messiah, the promised saviour of Israel. So John told them this:
 I baptize by immersing you in water. However, someone who is stronger than I am is coming; I am not worthy even to release the straps on his sandals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Synoptic Gospels</title>
      <link>https://tjfinney-messages.netlify.com/posts/2013-05-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tjfinney-messages.netlify.com/posts/2013-05-15/</guid>
      <description>Much in common Matthew, Mark, and Luke make up the three synoptic Gospels. These three have much in common but have unique elements as well. (Synoptic means “a general view, or a collection of heads or parts so arranged as to exhibit a general view of the whole.”)
Based on this chart1, would you venture to suggest a solution to the synoptic problem?
Gospels  What is a Gospel?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christian secrets</title>
      <link>https://tjfinney-messages.netlify.com/posts/2013-03-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tjfinney-messages.netlify.com/posts/2013-03-04/</guid>
      <description>Christians keeping secrets This Bible study looks at a few parts of the New Testament which hint that the first Christians were keeping some secrets. The initial trigger for this study was a sentence in the Acts of the Apostles that Karen Jobes pointed out in her commentary on 1 Peter.1 This sentence has been an eye-opener for me, a key to understanding some otherwise puzzling aspects of the New Testament.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Is Greatest?</title>
      <link>https://tjfinney-messages.netlify.com/posts/2012-11-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tjfinney-messages.netlify.com/posts/2012-11-18/</guid>
      <description>I love Mark&amp;rsquo;s Gospel. An early Christian named Papias said that
 Mark, having been Peter&amp;rsquo;s interpreter, wrote accurately though not in order all that he recalled of what was either said or done by the Lord. For he neither heard the Lord nor was he a follower of his but at a later date of Peter; who used to adapt his instuctions to the needs of the moment but not with a view to putting together the Lord&amp;rsquo;s sayings in orderly fashion: so that Mark did no wrong in thus writing some things as he recalled them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Four pillars</title>
      <link>https://tjfinney-messages.netlify.com/posts/2012-07-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tjfinney-messages.netlify.com/posts/2012-07-15/</guid>
      <description>Four early leaders Before I became a Christian I used to study a book called The Three Pillars of Zen. The subtitle tells us that these three pillars are teaching, practice, and enlightenment.1 Since becoming a Christian I have been studying another book, the New Testament, which began as twenty-seven individual writings that were later collected into four parts:
 the Four Gospels
 the Acts of the Apostles and the General Letters</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gospel wheel</title>
      <link>https://tjfinney-messages.netlify.com/posts/2011-08-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tjfinney-messages.netlify.com/posts/2011-08-03/</guid>
      <description>An old Christian symbol Here is a picture.
What do you think it is? It is actually a very old Christian symbol which represents a very good summary of the Gospel.
If you look closely, you might see that these Greek letters are contained in the wheel:
 Ι (iota)
 Χ (chi)
 Θ (theta)
 Υ (upsilon)
 Σ (sigma)
  This is what&amp;rsquo;s called an acrostic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One page</title>
      <link>https://tjfinney-messages.netlify.com/posts/2010-10-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tjfinney-messages.netlify.com/posts/2010-10-04/</guid>
      <description>One page of one book Sometimes people ask what book you would like to have if stuck on a desert island. These days many would prefer to take their favourite handheld device. That would be good until the batteries ran out unless you were lucky enough to have a solar-powered battery charger too. In some ways books are a better technology than electronic devices. You can drop them, leave them in the rain, or get sand in them and they still work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things I have found out about God</title>
      <link>https://tjfinney-messages.netlify.com/posts/2010-08-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tjfinney-messages.netlify.com/posts/2010-08-22/</guid>
      <description>An honour I am honoured to be able to speak at one of your final assemblies as Manning Uniting Church. I grew up among the people in this church and you played an important part in my upbringing. Despite being disinclined to listen, I heard the oracles of God from an early age. Not that I thought much of them at the time.
Today&amp;rsquo;s message is called “Things I have found out about God,” and there are a number of them so I had better hurry up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Christian communities</title>
      <link>https://tjfinney-messages.netlify.com/posts/2006-08-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tjfinney-messages.netlify.com/posts/2006-08-15/</guid>
      <description>Introduction  &amp;hellip; on this rock I will build my church. — Jesus Christ [Matt 16.18]
 The church is not a building but a Christian community built on the foundation of faith in Jesus Christ. In other words, it is a community of people who are convinced that Jesus Christ is the Messiah, the Son of the living God. A great deal of Christ&amp;rsquo;s teaching only makes sense in a community context.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://tjfinney-messages.netlify.com/posts/2020-11-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tjfinney-messages.netlify.com/posts/2020-11-30/</guid>
      <description>For those who trust him // Pandoc 2.9 adds attributes on both header and div. We remove the former (to // be compatible with the behavior of Pandoc :first-child&#34;); var i, h, a; for (i = 0; i 0) h.removeAttribute(a[0].name); } });  /*! jQuery v1.11.3 | (c) 2005, 2015 jQuery Foundation, Inc. | jquery.org/license */ !function(a,b){&#34;object&#34;==typeof module&amp;&amp;&#34;object&#34;==typeof module.exports?module.exports=a.document?b(a,!0):function(a){if(!a.document)throw new Error(&#34;jQuery requires a window with a document&#34;);return b(a)}:b(a)}(&#34;undefined&#34;!=typeof window?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>